Finding Aid for Bret Eynon papers, 1966-1977
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Bret Eynon papers 1966-1977
Eynon, Bret.
1 linear foot
85166 Aa 2
Student at the University of Michigan, collected materials relating to his interest in the radical causes and issues of the 1960s and 1970s.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Bret Eynon (donor no. 6451 ) and came to the library in 1980.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Bret Eynon was a researcher and historian of the "New Left" in Ann Arbor, Michigan in the 1960s. He later became director of the LaGuardia Center for Teaching and Learning.
The Bret Eynon collection consists of original and collected material relating to his interest in the radical causes and issues of the 1960s and 1970s. The files, arranged by topic, relate to the Black Action Movement (BAM) strike at the University of Michigan, John Sinclair, draft resistance, protests about the war in Vietnam, the Welfare Rights Organization, and feminism and the women's movement.
Subjects:
African Americans--Michigan.; Black Action Movement (University of Michigan); Feminism--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Draft.; Radicalism--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1971-1980.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975.; Welfare rights movement--Michigan.; Sinclair, John, 1941-; Women's rights--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Topical File
  - Ann Arbor High School newspaper, 1967-1972 (Box 1)
  - Black Action Movement (BAM) strike (Box 1)
  - Black Manifesto (Box 1)
  - Children's Community School (Box 1)
  - Contemporary History Project
    - Activities of respondents (Box 1)
    - Clippings (Box 1)
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Papers
      - "John Sinclair: Hipster" (essay by Bret Eynon) (Box 1)
      - Draft of paper (untitled) by Bret Eynon and Jill Irvine, 1977 (Box 1)
      - Draft of paper (untitled) (Box 1)
  - Event flyers (Box 1)
  - Feldman, Rich: personal history (Box 1)
  - Gay rights (Ann Arbor) (Box 1)
  - Government intelligence activities
    - COINTELPRO (Michigan)
      - 1962-1966 (Box 1)
      - 1968 (Box 1)
      - 1969-1970 (Box 1)
      - Human Rights Party and Radical Independent Party (Box 1)
      - Articles (Box 1)
    - COINTELPRO (National) (Box 1)
    - CIA
      - Memos and correspondence concerning contract with the University of Michigan (Box 1)
      - Project Resistance (Box 1)
  - Organizations (1970s)
    - Human Rights Party (Box 1)
    - New University Conference (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Project Outreach (Box 1)
  - Selective Service (P. Harris)
    - Reference File (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (SDS)
    - Voice newsletter, undated and 1963-1966 (Box 1)
    - Toledo Free Press, ca. 1966 (Box 1)
    - Recruiter protests, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Teach-in, November 1975
    - Clippings (Box 1)
    - Publicity (Box 1)
    - Reference file and organization lists (Box 1)
  - Welfare Rights Organization (WRO)
    - Adams, Joan (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor WRO (Box 1)
    - State and national (Box 1)
  - Women's movement
    - Family Planning Medical Services (Box 1)
    - Feminist Party (Box 1)